<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-10-27T10:43:04+00:00</updated><id>https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/feed.xml</id><title type="html">BuWiFi: WiFi Marketing Solution</title><subtitle>BuWiFi - WiFi Marketing Solution. Understand Your Customers and Engage Better. Transform your guest WiFi into a powerful WiFi marketing tool.
</subtitle><author><name>Murat Eren</name></author><entry><title type="html">Benefits of WiFi Analytics</title><link href="https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/guestwifi/marketing/2025/10/25/title-of-your-post.md.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Benefits of WiFi Analytics" /><published>2025-10-25T18:45:52+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-25T18:45:52+00:00</updated><id>https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/guestwifi/marketing/2025/10/25/title-of-your-post.md</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/guestwifi/marketing/2025/10/25/title-of-your-post.md.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="test">Test</h1>

<p>Test goes here</p>]]></content><author><name>Murat Eren</name></author><category term="GuestWiFi" /><category term="Marketing" /><category term="Gamification" /><category term="GuestWiFi" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Make it simple, branded and seamless for your customers to login anytime, at any of your venues]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/images/company/mobile-shopping.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/images/company/mobile-shopping.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Captive Portals Made Simple</title><link href="https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/marketing/2025/09/23/captive-portals.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Captive Portals Made Simple" /><published>2025-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/marketing/2025/09/23/captive-portals</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/marketing/2025/09/23/captive-portals.html"><![CDATA[<h1 class="markdown-h1" id="captive-portals-made-simple">Captive Portals Made Simple</h1>

<h2 class="text-muted mt-3 markdown-h2" id="what-they-are-and-why-they-matter">What They Are and Why They Matter</h2>

<p>You’ve probably seen a captive portal before -  it’s the WiFi login page that pops up when you connect in a café, airport, or shopping mall.
It asks you to agree to terms, type your email, or maybe watch a short ad before letting you online.</p>

<p>So, in simple terms: a captive portal is the front door to public WiFi.</p>

<h2 class="markdown-h2" id="benefits-for-different-groups">Benefits for Different Groups</h2>

<ul>
  <li>For End-Users
    <ul>
      <li>Free fast and reliable WiFi access instead of using mobile data.</li>
      <li>Extra perks like coupons, loyalty points, or travel updates shown during login.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>For Venue Owners (shops, malls, hotels, cafés)
    <ul>
      <li>Branding: the login page looks like your business, not a generic WiFi pop-up.</li>
      <li>Customer insights: collect basic data (with consent) to understand visits and repeat customers.</li>
      <li>Marketing: promote offers, events, or discounts right when people connect.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>For Telcos and WiFi Providers
    <ul>
      <li>Scalability: manage thousands of hotspots from one system.</li>
      <li>Revenue models: offer free basic WiFi and sell premium packages or sponsored access.</li>
      <li>Compliance: log consent and user sessions</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 class="markdown-h2" id="how-to-make-a-captive-portal">How to Make a Captive Portal</h2>

<ol>
  <li>Choose a platform - a solution like Linkyfi captive portal makes it easy to set up and customize.</li>
  <li>Design your login page - add your logo, colors, and messages.</li>
  <li>Pick access rules - free login, social media login, SMS code, or premium tiers.</li>
  <li>Add extras - coupons, surveys, or ads if you want to engage users.</li>
  <li>Launch and monitor - see how many users connect and how your campaigns perform.</li>
</ol>

<h2 class="markdown-h2" id="the-bottom-line">The Bottom Line</h2>

<p>A captive portal is more than just a WiFi login page. It’s a tool  that makes internet access engaging and useful for users, while giving  businesses and telcos a way to connect, market, and grow.
With solutions like Linkyfi, creating a captive portal takes minutes - and it can turn guest WiFi into a win-win for everyone.</p>

<p class="note">With Scratch &amp; Win game, Teknosa collects valuable presence and opt-in data and increases visit to sales conversion ratio.</p>

<h3 class="markdown-h3" id="how-it-works">How it works</h3>

<ol>
  <li>The customer enters the store and sees the Scratch &amp; Win campaign image</li>
  <li>Connects to Guest WiFi network from mobile phone</li>
  <li>Captive portal opens. He enters his phone, receives the verification SMS. Enters the verification code and Name</li>
  <li>Scratch &amp; Win SMS is sent to successfully registered customers</li>
</ol>

<p align="center" class="img-fluid rounded">
<img src="/buwifi-public/images/company/kazikazanpop.jpg" alt="drawing" width="350" />
</p>

<p>Here is a short demo video explaining the flow:</p>

<div class="position-relative">
<div class="bg-overlay rounded-md"></div>
 <img src="/buwifi-public/images/company/kazikazanekran.jpg" class="rounded img-fluid mx-auto d-block" alt="" />
 <div class="play-icon">
	<a href="#!" data-type="youtube" data-id="bAiFcFQRx0Q" class="play-btn lightbox">
		<i class="mdi mdi-play text-primary rounded-circle bg-white shadow"></i>
	</a>
	<h4 class="title fw-bold text-white mb-2 mt-2">Scratch &amp; Win Demo</h4>
	<p class="text-white mx-auto para-desc mb-0">Very effective gamification usecase</p>
 </div>
 </div>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 class="markdown-h2" id="are-you-ready-to-grow-your-business-with-wifi-marketing">Are you ready to grow your business with WiFi marketing?</h2>

<p>Contact us to  find out how <span class="text-primary fw-bold">BuWiFi</span> measures offline customer behavior and builds customer loyalty. Leverage your Guest WiFi to gain a competitive edge.</p>]]></content><author><name>Murat Eren</name></author><category term="Marketing" /><category term="Gamification" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Captive Portals Made Simple]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Get Your Customers to Engage With Guest WiFi Using Gamification</title><link href="https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/marketing/2022/03/07/scratch-and-win.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Get Your Customers to Engage With Guest WiFi Using Gamification" /><published>2022-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/marketing/2022/03/07/scratch-and-win</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/marketing/2022/03/07/scratch-and-win.html"><![CDATA[<h1 class="markdown-h1" id="how-to-get-your-customers-to-engage-with-guest-wifi-using-gamification">How to Get Your Customers to Engage With Guest WiFi Using Gamification</h1>

<h2 class="text-muted mt-3 markdown-h2" id="scratch--win-usecase-is-a-successful-gamification-scenario-to-engage-visiting-customers">Scratch &amp; Win usecase is a successful gamification scenario to engage visiting customers</h2>

<p>Guest WiFi is one of the most requested guest amenities.  It serves as a channel to collect customer data in real-time. This valuable data will give you a clear picture of how customers interacts with your venue.</p>

<p>Gamification is the integration of gaming elements, such as sweepstakes, free coupons, scoring points and, competing with other people for some reward on a digital platform in order to encourage participation on this platform.
When you combine gamification with your Guest WiFi, and you have got yourself an entertaining data-collector.</p>

<p>Using Guest WiFi registration process, during or after,  you can give your customers free gifts, coupons and  a fun time by having them play an exciting game while you gather vital information.</p>

<h2 class="markdown-h2" id="scratch--win-kazı-kazan-is-a-successful-gamification-scenario-to-engage-visiting-customers">Scratch &amp; Win (Kazı Kazan) is a successful gamification scenario to engage visiting customers</h2>

<p>Customers who connect to Guest WiFi (as a new registration or login) can participate Scratch &amp; Win game and get a discount gift voucher at Teknosa stores. We have distributed 1000s of discount coupons using this game.</p>

<p class="note">With Scratch &amp; Win game, Teknosa collects valuable presence and opt-in data and increases visit to sales conversion ratio.</p>

<h3 class="markdown-h3" id="how-it-works">How it works</h3>

<ol>
  <li>The customer enters the store and sees the Scratch &amp; Win campaign image</li>
  <li>Connects to Guest WiFi network from mobile phone</li>
  <li>Captive portal opens. He enters his phone, receives the verification SMS. Enters the verification code and Name</li>
  <li>Scratch &amp; Win SMS is sent to successfully registered customers</li>
</ol>

<p align="center" class="img-fluid rounded">
<img src="/buwifi-public/images/company/kazikazanpop.jpg" alt="drawing" width="350" />
</p>

<p>Here is a short demo video explaining the flow:</p>

<div class="position-relative">
<div class="bg-overlay rounded-md"></div>
 <img src="/buwifi-public/images/company/kazikazanekran.jpg" class="rounded img-fluid mx-auto d-block" alt="" />
 <div class="play-icon">
	<a href="#!" data-type="youtube" data-id="bAiFcFQRx0Q" class="play-btn lightbox">
		<i class="mdi mdi-play text-primary rounded-circle bg-white shadow"></i>
	</a>
	<h4 class="title fw-bold text-white mb-2 mt-2">Scratch &amp; Win Demo</h4>
	<p class="text-white mx-auto para-desc mb-0">Very effective gamification usecase</p>
 </div>
 </div>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 class="markdown-h2" id="are-you-ready-to-grow-your-business-with-wifi-marketing">Are you ready to grow your business with WiFi marketing?</h2>

<p>Contact us to  find out how <span class="text-primary fw-bold">BuWiFi</span> measures offline customer behavior and builds customer loyalty. Leverage your Guest WiFi to gain a competitive edge.</p>]]></content><author><name>Murat Eren</name></author><category term="Marketing" /><category term="Gamification" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to Get Your Customers to Engage With Guest WiFi Using Gamification]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is Guest WiFi?</title><link href="https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/guestwifi/2022/02/26/what-is-guestwifi.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is Guest WiFi?" /><published>2022-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/guestwifi/2022/02/26/what-is-guestwifi</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/guestwifi/2022/02/26/what-is-guestwifi.html"><![CDATA[<h1 class="markdown-h1" id="what-is-guest-wifi">What is Guest WiFi?</h1>

<h2 class="text-muted mt-3 markdown-h2" id="deliver-a-branded-digital-experience-to-on-site-visitors--turn-guest-wifi-into-a-powerful-marketing-channel">Deliver a Branded, Digital Experience to On-Site Visitors &amp; Turn Guest WiFi into a powerful Marketing Channel</h2>

<p>With more than 80% of the population owning a smartphone, your customers expect fast, free and user-friendly guest WiFi wherever they go. 
Guest WiFi is one of the most requested guest amenities and providing digital connectivity to your visitors is an expected utility. 
For many people, accessing Guest WiFi is one of the first actions they take once they arrive at a physical space. 
This makes the Guest WiFi experience often the first touch point for interaction with your guests.</p>

<p>Businesses understand this need for connectivity, but often overlook the Guest WiFi channel as part of an omni-channel strategy.</p>

<p>Omni-channel experiences are about leveraging data to develop physical experiences that act, behave, and can be understood like digital experiences.</p>

<p class="note">Guest WiFi marketing is a critical tool within an omni-channel marketing strategy, whether you are a larger retailer, a shopping mall, a museum, or a co-working space.</p>

<p><img src="/buwifi-public/images/company/guest-wifi-hero.jpg" alt="an image alt text" title="Guest WiFi must be simple" class="img-fluid rounded" /></p>

<h2 class="markdown-h2" id="key-benefits">Key Benefits</h2>

<h3 class="markdown-h3" id="delight-your-guests-with-easy-wifi-connectivity">Delight your guests with easy WiFi connectivity</h3>

<p>Create an easy login portal and onboard guests with our simple user interface. When guests return to your venue the network remembers their details. Customers will spend more time and money in a venue offering guest WiFi.</p>

<h3 class="markdown-h3" id="enrich-crm-data">Enrich CRM Data</h3>

<p>Collect and unify offline (In-store visits, Guest WiFi, POS and loyalty programs) and online (Website and app, Ecommerce, Digital Marketing) customer touchpoint data.</p>

<p>Every time a customer signs into your Guest WiFi, it is an opportunity to identify and validate that customer’s profile. Once a valid profile is secured, it enables personalized content that is relative to the individual, delivered in the moment, and is based on past behavior. This customer authentication - using guest WiFi - can be the bridge between your company’s CRM system and its foot traffic and closing this gap means more valid user profiles and better marketing ROI.</p>

<p>Guest WiFi data is also first party data, defined as data collected directly from your audience. When you leverage Guest WiFi as a marketing channel, 100% of that data comes from first-party relationships with clear consumer opt-ins vs. second or third-party data that can come from a myriad of sources.</p>

<p class="note">Properly obtaining and leveraging 1st party data has become an increasingly important topic as data privacy and GDPR-like regulations continue to be an intensely debated topic both domestically and abroad.</p>

<h3 class="markdown-h3" id="collect-and-monetize-your-opt-in-shopper-data-with-wifi-marketing">Collect and monetize your opt-in shopper data with WiFi marketing​</h3>

<p>Transform your WiFi network into a powerful marketing asset that builds customer database, promotes business and collects valuable insights.</p>

<h2 class="markdown-h2" id="are-you-ready-to-grow-your-business-with-wifi-marketing">Are you ready to grow your business with WiFi marketing?</h2>

<p>Contact us to  find out how <span class="text-primary fw-bold">BuWiFi</span> measures offline customer behavior and builds customer loyalty. Leverage your Guest WiFi to gain a competitive edge</p>]]></content><author><name>Murat Eren</name></author><category term="GuestWiFi" /><category term="GuestWiFi" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What is Guest WiFi?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is WiFi Marketing?</title><link href="https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/marketing/2022/02/01/what-is-wifi-marketing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is WiFi Marketing?" /><published>2022-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/marketing/2022/02/01/what-is-wifi-marketing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/marketing/2022/02/01/what-is-wifi-marketing.html"><![CDATA[<h1 class="markdown-h1" id="what-is-wifi-marketing">What is WiFi Marketing?</h1>

<h2 class="text-muted mt-3 markdown-h2" id="collect-customer-data-and-see-trends-and-results-of-marketing-campaigns-with-wifi-analytics">Collect customer data and see trends and results of marketing campaigns with WiFi Analytics</h2>

<p>WiFi marketing is a marketing technique that uses Guest WiFi to collect &amp; clean customer data such as names, emails, phone numbers, customer behavior, and demographics.</p>

<p>This data is used to personalize marketing campaigns to increase customer loyalty, build online reviews, and save at risk customers.</p>

<p>Also, the performance of every campaign can be tracked down to the tangible ROI of a customer walking back in your door.</p>

<p class="note"><strong>WiFi Marketing</strong> allows business owners and marketers to send targeted advertising and behavior-driven promotions to people, via online advertising and email marketing, to customers who have logged into your Guest WiFi.</p>

<h2 class="markdown-h2" id="wifi-analytics-is-important-for-effective-wifi-marketing">WiFi Analytics is important for effective WiFi Marketing</h2>

<p>WiFi Analytics is the process of collecting and analyzing anonymous data from WiFi-enabled devices through WiFi access points.  This provides key performance indicators (KPIs) such as dwell times, frequency, and other advanced location analytics for physical locations.</p>

<p>Once a customer opts into the Guest WiFi landing page, their individual presence analytics are associated to the customers profile. This process enables our WiFi marketing platform, <span class="text-primary fw-bold">BuWiFi</span>, to track the performance of all campaigns sent to customers down to someone walking back into their door.</p>

<h2 class="markdown-h2" id="how-are-customer-profiles-built-with-wifi-marketing">How Are Customer Profiles Built with WiFi Marketing?</h2>

<p>A customer profile is a description of a business’ customers typically stored in a company’s customer relationship management software (CRM). It includes demographics, behavior data, zip codes, birthdays and customer contact information, such as email address or phone number.</p>

<p>With integration, our Enterprise WiFi marketing solution, <span class="text-primary fw-bold">BuWiFi</span>, automatically build customer profiles for physical locations by combining customer data from Guest WiFi landing page.</p>

<h2 class="markdown-h2" id="key-benefits-of-wifi-marketing">Key Benefits of WiFi Marketing</h2>

<p class="note">With <strong>WiFi Marketing</strong>, retailers can increase customer engagement, footfall traffic and dwell time with personalized offers, sweepstakes and surveys.</p>

<h3 class="markdown-h3" id="personalise-and-enhance-shopper-experience">Personalise and Enhance Shopper Experience</h3>

<p>With WiFi Marketing, venue owners can deliver location based, personalised content and  reach your customers via SMS at the right time and location.</p>

<h4 class="markdown-h3" id="engage-your-customers-through-smarter-campaigns-and-sweepstakes">Engage your customers through smarter campaigns and sweepstakes</h4>

<p><span class="text-primary fw-bold">BuWiFi</span> is a powerful <strong>marketing automation solution</strong> where you create automated messaging and see measurable results. 
Drive in-store conversion with personalized offers, automatically delivered to customers when they enter your store, engage with a department, or after they leave.</p>

<h4 class="markdown-h3" id="increase-dwell-time-loyalty-and-generate-new-revenue-streams-for-your-business">Increase dwell time, loyalty and generate new revenue streams for your business</h4>

<p>Increase foot traffic &amp; dwell time with personalized offers. Build happy, satisfied, brand loyal customers that come back time and time again.</p>

<h2 class="markdown-h2" id="are-you-ready-to-grow-your-business-with-wifi-marketing">Are you ready to grow your business with WiFi marketing?</h2>

<p>Contact us to  find out how <span class="text-primary fw-bold">BuWiFi</span> measures offline customer behavior and builds customer loyalty. Leverage your Guest WiFi to gain a competitive edge</p>]]></content><author><name>Murat Eren</name></author><category term="Marketing" /><category term="Marketing" /><category term="Analytics" /><category term="GuestWiFi" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What is WiFi Marketing?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/images/company/mobile-shopping.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/images/company/mobile-shopping.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Benefits of WiFi Analytics</title><link href="https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/analytics/2022/01/25/benefits-of-wifi-analytics.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Benefits of WiFi Analytics" /><published>2022-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/analytics/2022/01/25/benefits-of-wifi-analytics</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/analytics/2022/01/25/benefits-of-wifi-analytics.html"><![CDATA[<h1 class="markdown-h1" id="benefits-of-wifi-analytics">Benefits of WiFi Analytics</h1>

<h2 class="text-muted mt-3 markdown-h2" id="understand-your-customers-better">Understand your customers better</h2>

<blockquote>
  <p class="md-blockquote">Without data you’re just another person with an opinion.<br />
W. Edwards Deming<br />
Data Scientist</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Footfall cameras just count heads but WiFi Analytics goes beyond that: You measure, understand and boost store performance with WiFi Analytics.</p>

<p>Our solution, <span class="text-primary fw-bold">BuWiFi</span>, enables you to collect key customer data and begin to understand how visitors interact within your venue. We offer advanced presence analytics for venue owners to understand the location potential and success in getting visitors inside a store.</p>

<h2 class="markdown-h2" id="how-can-in-store-analytics-benefit-a-business">How can in-store analytics benefit a business?</h2>
<p>The most common advantages of WiFi Analytics includes:</p>

<h3 class="markdown-h3" id="1-get-rich-metrics-and-actionable-insights-of-in-store-shopping-behaviour">1. Get rich metrics and actionable insights of in-store shopping behaviour</h3>

<p>Get the same common web metrics and reach par with online stores. Create custom audiences based on demographics such as age, gender, and shopping behaviour.</p>

<h3 class="markdown-h3" id="2-enrich-crm-data">2. Enrich CRM Data</h3>

<p>Collect and unify offline (In-store visits, Guest WiFi, POS and loyalty programs) and online (Website and app, Ecommerce, Digital Marketing) customer touchpoint data.</p>

<h3 class="markdown-h3" id="3-collect-and-monetize-your-opt-in-shopper-data-with-wifi-marketing">3. Collect and monetize your opt-in shopper data with WiFi marketing</h3>

<p>Transform your WiFi network into a powerful marketing asset that builds customer database, promotes business and collects valuable insights.</p>

<h2 class="markdown-h2" id="the-bottom-line">The Bottom Line</h2>

<p>In-store analytics can connect the dots between the consumer, the store and the buying decision. It is a great way to learn more about how the store is able to attract customers and help retailers to optimize customer experience.</p>

<p>With the help of BuWiFi, you are able to understand why customers visit your store, how they behave inside the store and what are the reasons behind them leaving empty handed.</p>

<p class="note">BuWiFi is an inexpensive, lightweight and highly scalable analytics solution for understanding in-store customer behaviour and loyalty patterns.
It is an effective solution that can drive sales and ensure customers enjoy shopping at your store.</p>]]></content><author><name>Murat Eren</name></author><category term="Analytics" /><category term="Data" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Benefits of WiFi Analytics]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bridge the online/offline data gap</title><link href="https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/analytics/2022/01/15/online-offline-data-gap.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bridge the online/offline data gap" /><published>2022-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/analytics/2022/01/15/online-offline-data-gap</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/analytics/2022/01/15/online-offline-data-gap.html"><![CDATA[<h1 class="markdown-h1" id="bridge-the-onlineoffline-data-gap">Bridge the online/offline data gap</h1>

<h2 class="text-muted mt-3 markdown-h2" id="wifi-analytics-brings-offline-retailers-par-with-online">WiFi analytics brings offline retailers par with online</h2>

<p>Online retailers can accurately target customers. Every customer touch point is measurable.
Brick-and-mortar retailers retailers, on the other hand, have long been at a disadvantage to online businesses in terms of customer data collection.</p>

<h2 class="markdown-h2" id="offline-retailers-want-to">Offline retailers want to…</h2>

<ul>
  <li>Measure and understand with the same level of depth and personalization as e-tailers have</li>
  <li>Engage with your customers in the store at the point of purchase</li>
</ul>

<h2 class="markdown-h2" id="-but-they-dont-have-the-same-tools-as-e-tailers-have">… but they don’t have the same tools as e-tailers have</h2>

<ul>
  <li>Footfall counters at doors:
    <ul>
      <li>Counts only number of people</li>
      <li>No opt-in customer data for engagement and personalization</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Transactional data from POS systems:
    <ul>
      <li>Small sample size of customers: On average 80% customers leave the store without any purchase</li>
      <li>No engagement/loyalty data
        <ul>
          <li>No dwell time</li>
          <li>Visit frequency</li>
          <li>Engagement rate</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Surveys:
    <ul>
      <li>Small data: Only gives businesses a “snapshot in time” of a small sample size of customers</li>
      <li>Expensive</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Native Apps:
    <ul>
      <li>Low download rates</li>
      <li>Low active users</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 class="markdown-h2" id="online---offline-data-gap-causes-major-issues">Online - Offline data gap causes major issues</h2>

<ul>
  <li>Offline is still the king since 9 out of 10$ are still spent in store.</li>
  <li>On average 80% customers leave the store without any purchase.</li>
  <li>Digital interactions influence 64% of those purchase decisions
    <ul>
      <li>So when you engage properly with customers in-store, the opportunity is huge.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Therefore offline retailers must invest in technology and analytics so they can harness the power of data and personalize their offers.</p>

<h2 class="markdown-h2" id="fortunately-wifi-analytics-can-resolve-this-issue-for-businesses-of-any-size">Fortunately, WiFi analytics can resolve this issue for businesses of any size</h2>

<p>Just Imagine</p>
<ul>
  <li>Obtaining detailed, real-time analytics data on each and every shopper returning to your store,</li>
  <li>And optimizing and personalizing the shopping experience based on such data</li>
</ul>

<p class="note">With <strong>WiFi Analytics</strong>, retailers can bridge the online/offline data gap. They can better target their marketing and brand building efforts across multiple consumer touchpoints to better meet the demand for the modern customer experience.</p>]]></content><author><name>Murat Eren</name></author><category term="Analytics" /><category term="Data" /><category term="Omnichannel" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bridge the online/offline data gap]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is WiFi Analytics?</title><link href="https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/analytics/2022/01/01/what-is-wifi-analytics.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is WiFi Analytics?" /><published>2022-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/analytics/2022/01/01/what-is-wifi-analytics</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://buwifi.github.io/buwifi-public/analytics/2022/01/01/what-is-wifi-analytics.html"><![CDATA[<h1 class="markdown-h1" id="what-is-wifi-analytics">What is WiFi Analytics?</h1>

<h2 class="text-muted mt-3 markdown-h2" id="collect-customer-data-and-see-trends-and-results-of-marketing-campaigns-with-wifi-analytics">Collect customer data and see trends and results of marketing campaigns with WiFi Analytics</h2>

<p>WiFi analytics, also known as Presence analytics, is the process of collecting &amp; analyzing customer behavior data from WiFi access points to report KPIs such as customer traffic, dwell time, and engagement rate.</p>

<p>This is tracked using mobile phones and your physical location’s WiFi access point(s) (AP).</p>

<p>Every mobile device – smart phone, tablet, laptop – has a unique identifying number called a MAC address. Every connected device broadcasts an anonymous signal. When WiFi is activated on the device, it broadcasts a signal (probe request) that “looks” for a WiFi AP. Probe request contains the device’s MAC address.</p>

<p>WiFi APs look for signals from WiFi-enabled devices within range. So when AP identifies a device within range, it starts collecting anonymous customer presence data.  Users do not have to log into the WiFi for this to occur.</p>

<p>With Presence data, BuWiFi provides some very important metrics like:</p>
<ul class="custom_list">
  <li>Total Passersby</li>
  <li>Total Visitors: Floor/Zone breakdown</li>
  <li>Dwell times:  Long/Short Visit</li>
  <li>Day of week/hour of day</li>
  <li>Engagement/Bounce rate</li>
  <li>Heatmap</li>
</ul>

<p>These metrics are valuable in terms of being able to get a clear picture of your venue’s foot traffic and loyalty rates.</p>

<ul class="custom_list">
  <li>If you have multiple stores, you can compare different stores to each other.</li>
  <li>If you have big campuses like shopping mall, you can see heatmaps, floor/zone breakdown of each metrics.</li>
</ul>

<blockquote class="md-blockquote">
  <h2 class="markdown-h3" id="turn-data-into-powerful-insights">Turn data into powerful insights</h2>

  <p>BuWiFi translates anonymous device data into customer intelligence. We help you to understand visitor behavior, shopping patterns, and store performance metrics.</p>
  <ul>
    <li>Get rich metrics and actionable insights of in-store shopping behaviour</li>
    <li>Enrich CRM Data</li>
    <li>Collect and monetize your opt-in shopper data</li>
  </ul>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Murat Eren</name></author><category term="Analytics" /><category term="Data" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What is WiFi Analytics?]]></summary></entry></feed>